<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>My site</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/</id><updated>2024-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>noticiasFiltradas-en</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/noticiasfiltradas-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2024-03-09:/pelican/en/noticiasfiltradas-en.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="en"></category></entry><entry><title>resultadosbusqueda-en</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/resultadosbusqueda-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2024-03-09:/pelican/en/resultadosbusqueda-en.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="en"></category></entry><entry><title>historia-en</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/historia-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-03-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2024-03-07:/pelican/en/historia-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;STORY AND PROMOTIONAL VIDEO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two centuries of history support the trajectory of the &lt;strong&gt;University of Córdoba&lt;/strong&gt;, which, founded as such in 1972, has its roots in the Free University that operated in the province at the end of the 19th century and has centuries-old studies such as those of Veterinary …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;STORY AND PROMOTIONAL VIDEO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two centuries of history support the trajectory of the &lt;strong&gt;University of Córdoba&lt;/strong&gt;, which, founded as such in 1972, has its roots in the Free University that operated in the province at the end of the 19th century and has centuries-old studies such as those of Veterinary, unique in Andalusia. Its youth and its average size - the &lt;strong&gt;UCO&lt;/strong&gt; has 21,000 students; just over 1,200 professors and 700 workers - have given it the necessary dynamism to adapt and enter the 21st century as a University of high teaching quality and proven scientific solvency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UCO&lt;/strong&gt;'s studies range from Humanities and Legal-Social Sciences to Health Sciences and scientific-technical careers, three areas that correspond to its structure in three large campuses: social legal, integrated in the urban center; the Health one, to the west of the capital, and the agri-food, scientific and technical one of Rabanales, in the eastern area. In addition, the &lt;strong&gt;UCO&lt;/strong&gt; has the Belmez Polytechnic School, located sixty kilometers from the capital of Córdoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rabanales campus constitutes the best proof of the modernization process that characterizes the University. Its facilities accommodate the most advanced infrastructure for research and teaching, while integrating a whole series of complementary services that make it one of the most outstanding teaching complexes in Andalusia. Rabanales concentrates a good part of the scientific production of the University, located at the forefront of research in the Andalusian autonomous community and among the most relevant research institutions at the national level. Both research and teaching are understood at the &lt;strong&gt;University of Córdoba&lt;/strong&gt; as the two great pillars of the institution, always with the same goal: quality. Added to this objective is the leading role that the UCO is playing in the development of the &lt;strong&gt;European Higher Education Area&lt;/strong&gt;. Teaching, Research, Quality and Europe are, therefore, the maxims that currently govern the life of the University.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="en"></category></entry><entry><title>index</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2024-02-27:/pelican/en/index.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="en"></category></entry><entry><title>noticia3-en</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/noticia3-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2024-02-27:/pelican/en/noticia3-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;AUPA aims to “make a logical, coherent and responsible offer” of degrees and calls for “quality, strategy and equal conditions” with respect to private universities.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Association of Rectors of Andalusian Public Universities (AUPA) met today at the University of Cádiz to establish criteria from the Andalusian university system in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;AUPA aims to “make a logical, coherent and responsible offer” of degrees and calls for “quality, strategy and equal conditions” with respect to private universities.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Association of Rectors of Andalusian Public Universities (AUPA) met today at the University of Cádiz to establish criteria from the Andalusian university system in relation to the new map of degrees and to address different priority issues in the field of academic organization such as micro-credits or micro-credentials, master's degrees or European consortia. The session was chaired by the acting rector of the UCA, Francisco Piniella, as host of the meeting, and by the rector of the Pablo de Olavide University, Francisco Oliva, current president of AUPA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the initial session of AUPA that opened the morning agenda before the vice-rectors of Academic Organization meet in parallel in three sectors to study the topics planned in the content program, the rectors of the public universities Andalusians has appeared publicly to report on the issues addressed. In the words of the president of AUPA, “we have met fundamentally to analyze how to implement a new decree for the organization of university teaching, which is very important for the Andalusian public university system since the current one was established in 2010 and has not undergone changes. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context, Francisco Oliva has pointed out, “we are in the process of the 4.0 revolution, the green revolution or equality and many other changes that require an adaptation of our universities. This decree gives new possibilities to do new degrees in Andalusia and what we intend is to make a logical, coherent and responsible offer. “We are a unique public university system and we want to respond in the best way to the training needs of our community.” For this reason, he added, “we do not intend to compete between universities but rather coordinate and make a coherent offer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, the rector of the UPO has indicated that we must work in three areas: “being able to offer joint degrees, promoting the internationalization of universities through the recruitment of foreign students with an attractive offer and long-term training. of a lifetime so that all people throughout their lives continue training at the university through the micro-credential system where the Andalusian universities are already working with the aim of making a competitive, rational and that offers the best possible training to citizens in Andalusia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the creation of private universities, the president of AUPA recalled that the position of the Association of Rectors of Andalusian Public Universities “has been very clear for some time. First of all, we demand that all quality requirements required of any university be strictly met, in addition to competing on equal terms. “The strict requirements to offer a degree do not exist in the private sector.” Furthermore, he has specified the need to have “a general university strategy with respect to private ones, which are fully legal, but demanding quality, strategy and equal conditions.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="en"></category><category term="Aupa"></category><category term="Public Universities of Andalusia"></category><category term="Degrees"></category><category term="academic organization"></category><category term="private universities"></category></entry><entry><title>index</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/es/index.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2024-02-27:/pelican/es/index.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="es"></category></entry><entry><title>noticia4-en</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/noticia4-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2024-02-12:/pelican/en/noticia4-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;In the latest edition of the ranking, the UCO improves its classification, going from 772nd to 744th. At the national level it is ranked 16th and continues to be second in Andalusia.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Córdoba maintains its position among the 800 best universities in the world, according to the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;In the latest edition of the ranking, the UCO improves its classification, going from 772nd to 744th. At the national level it is ranked 16th and continues to be second in Andalusia.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Córdoba maintains its position among the 800 best universities in the world, according to the latest edition of &lt;a href=""&gt;THE Ranking (Times Higher Education World University Ranking)&lt;/a&gt;. The UCO, although it continues in the range of the 600-801 best universities, improves its ranking and goes from 772 to 744, rising 28 positions. At the national level, the University of Córdoba is ranked 16th out of 60 Spanish universities. It continues to be the second in Andalusia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The THE Ranking, one of the most prestigious internationally, lists a total of 1,904 universities from 108 countries and measures, through 18 indicators, the learning environment, the research environment, the quality of research, the international perspective and the industry. These 5 groups of indicators define, through surveys, data captured from universities and scientific information providers such as Scopus, the set of aspects that best define, according to their methodology, the common characteristics of the world's universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a global level, the UCO rises positions in this post-covid era where research work seriously suffered from the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This positioning is due to the growth, in general, of the aforementioned indicators, increasing scores in four of the five analyzed and going from a final score of 34.34 in the 2023 ranking to 38.11 in this last 2024 ranking (11% ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scores by groups of indicators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research and teaching health of the University of Córdoba continues to have an impact on international rankings despite the difficult past period. At a time when the world situation in every sense is beginning to regain inertia, research activity is beginning to show signs of the efforts of the research staff at the University of Córdoba.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="en"></category><category term="ránkings"></category><category term="ranking THE"></category><category term="Aupa"></category></entry><entry><title>noticia5-en</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/noticia5-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2024-02-12:/pelican/en/noticia5-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;More than twenty-five years ago, &lt;a href="#"&gt;photographer Gervasio Sánchez&lt;/a&gt; began documenting the effects of landmines on the population of places with war conflicts. It is a journalistic work that he has been developing for a quarter of a century, entering with empathy into the lives of its protagonists. The result is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;More than twenty-five years ago, &lt;a href="#"&gt;photographer Gervasio Sánchez&lt;/a&gt; began documenting the effects of landmines on the population of places with war conflicts. It is a journalistic work that he has been developing for a quarter of a century, entering with empathy into the lives of its protagonists. The result is the book 'Mined Lives. 25 years', a work that was presented at the UCO and will be signed with an exhibition in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="en"></category><category term="UCO"></category><category term="laucoenabierto"></category><category term="video"></category><category term="Gervasio Sánchez"></category><category term="photography"></category></entry><entry><title>noticia6-en</title><link href="https://davidvm29.github.io/pelican/en/noticia6-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-11-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>David Villen Moreno</name></author><id>tag:davidvm29.github.io,2023-11-24:/pelican/en/noticia6-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Sara Muñoz Porras, a 5th year student of the joint itinerary of Translation and Interpretation and Hispanic Philology, has been proclaimed the new president of the Student Council of the University of Córdoba (CEUCO) by an absolute majority after the elections held last Tuesday, October 25.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sara Muñoz was until …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Sara Muñoz Porras, a 5th year student of the joint itinerary of Translation and Interpretation and Hispanic Philology, has been proclaimed the new president of the Student Council of the University of Córdoba (CEUCO) by an absolute majority after the elections held last Tuesday, October 25.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sara Muñoz was until now the director of the CEUCO Activities Committee and now succeeds Juan José Morente Collado in the position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new president of CEUCO has commented that her objective this year is "to put an end to the reconstruction that Juanjo started last year because, without a doubt, we have recovered our work dynamics that he was looking for. In addition, training continues to be in our sights. Without it, the replacement would not be possible and, for example, I would not be here today, on the verge of major regulatory changes both internally by the new rectoral team, as well as at the regional and national level, and with a great team working behind me."&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="en"></category><category term="students"></category><category term="student representation"></category><category term="CEUCO"></category></entry></feed>